Register of the Japan, Koshikan (Korea) records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Confidential correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea to the Home Office, (Meiji 31-nen kimitsu honsho oshin), 1898; 197 frames.
  Confidential correspondence from Japanese Chargé d'Affaires in Korea Kato Masuo to Japanese Foreign Minister Nishi relating to the Russian recognition of Korea's adoption of the new name of Empire and the Korean King's adoption of the title of Emperor. A letter from Tsar Nicholas II to the Korean Emperor. Documents relating to the purchase of the Independence Press from Dr. Philip Jaisohn; Russia's reduction of troops in Korea; the publication of Hans0ng Il-bo ( Seoul Daily News); Russian land acquisitions at Chinnamp'o, Mokp'o, and on the island of Ch0ly0ng; anti-Russian sentiments in Korea; and the alleged poisoning of the Emperor and the Crown Prince. Confidential documents relating to the British mining concessions; Prince Ito's visit to China and Korea; political conditions in northeastern Korea; Russo-Japanese friction in Korea; and the public demonstration instigated by the Independence Club. Record of the audience given by the Korean Emperor to the Japanese Chargé d'Affaires Hioki Eki. Hioki's confidential report to Japanese Foreign Minister Aoki on secret Russian advisers in Korea. Jan. 12 - Dec. 13, 1898.
  55 contains statistical chart. 3b, 219 in English.
- Reports of the Japanese Legation in Korea to the Home Office, (Meiji 31-nen honsho o hokoku), 1898; 197 frames. (Reel 5)
  Box/Folder 2: 62.
  Documents relating to Russian military advisers in Korea; the Russian attempt to purchase the Kohado Island in Mokp'o harbor; and French and German concessions in Korea. July 11, 1898.
- Confidential correspondence to and from Japanese consular posts in Korea, (Meiji 31-nen kaku ryojikan kimitsu orai shin), 1898; 132 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 63.
  Documents relating to the Japanese coal dump on Ch0ly0ng Island; Prince Ito's visit to Korea and his conversations regarding Russo-Japanese negotiations on Korea; the arrival of a Russian warship in Pusan; the establishment of a Russian coal dump at Pusan; German land purchase on Ch0ly0ng Island; and the activities of Russian military officers in Pyongyang. List of foreigners employed in the Korean customs. Mar. 21 - Nov. 24, 1898.
  Illegible frames: 7, 106, 113, 121b. 76b, 87, 88a, 96b contain maps. 124b, 125a, 126a, 132a contain statistical charts. 47, 126b contain statistical charts in English. 36b in Korean.
- Diplomatic correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Korean government, (Meiji 31-nen Gaibu orai), 1898; 122 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 64.
  Correspondence between Japanese Minister in Korea Kato Masuo and Korean Foreign Ministers Cho Py0ng-i and Yi To-jae concerning the international postal service in Korea and the Japanese instructors for the Japanese Language School in Seoul. Communication between Kato and Korean Foreign Minister Pak Che-sun. Jan. 22 - Dec. 14, 1898.
  Two frames numbered 87. 41, 42, 95b, 96a in Korean.
- Miscellany, (Meiji 31-nen zakken), 1898; 11 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 66.
  Confidential reports submitted by Governor of Fukuoka Prefecture Sogabe Michio to Japanese Foreign Minister Okuma and Nishi Tokujiro concerning the activities of the Korean political refugee Pak Y0ng-hyo in Japan. July 14 - 20, 1898.
- Correspondence to and from Japanese consular posts in Korea, (Meiji 32-nen kaku ryojikan ofuku), 1899; 64 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 67.
  Documents relating to the Japanese purchase of land in Masan, Russian sailors' misconduct in Pusan, and Russian timber concessions on the Ullungdo Island. Apr. 17 - Oct. 23, 1899.
  Illegible frames: 11, 17, 55.
- Documents relating to the purchase of the Mokp'o Kohado Island, (Meiji 32-nen Moppo Kokato baishu shorui), 1899; 160 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 68.
  Reports from the Japanese Consul at Mokp'o Morikawa Kishiro to Japanese Minister in Korea Kato Masuo relating to the Russian attempts to purchase Kohado Island in Mokp'o harbor. Consul Morikawa's report to Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi relating to the purchase of Kohado Island by the Japanese. Texts of a contract for the lease of Kohado Island for 30 years between Yi Yun-yong and a Japanese, Shibuya Tatsutaro. Nov. 14, 1898 - Nov. 15, 1899.
  Missing frame: 13. Illegible fr.: 32, 125.
- Correspondence to and from the Japanese consular posts in Korea, (Meiji 32-nen kaku ryojikan ofuku), 1899; 42 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 69.
  Documents relating to the popular uprising at Kobu in the North Ch0lla Province. A detailed report on the Pyongyang area. June 6, 1899 - Jan. 8, 1900.
  Illegible frames: 11, 32, 35.
- Confidential correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea to the Home Office, --Part I (Meiji 32-nen kimitsu honsho o jo), 1899; 333 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 70.
  Confidential correspondence from Japanese Minister in Korea Kato Masuo to Japanese Foreign Minister Aoki relating to the arrival of the Chinese Minister to Seoul; the return of political refugees to Korea; the alleged secret audience between the Korean Emperor and the Russian Minister to Korea; and the publication of Hans0ng Ilbo. Texts of the agreement between the Korean Foreign Office and Russian Count Henry Keyserling concerning the lease of land at Ulchin, Changjin, and Chinp'odo Island. Kato's confidential report relating to anti-Japanese sentiments among the Russian, French, and American Ministers to Korea. Documents relating to the removal of the Korean King from the Russian Legation, and Russo-American relations in Korea. Record of an audience granted by the Korean Emperor to Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi. Jan. 21 - June 24, 1899.
  Illegible frame: 160. 159, 160 on the same frame. 158, 159 in English.
- Confidential correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea to the Home Office, --Part II (Meiji 32-nen kimitsu honsho o ge), 1899; 287 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 71.
  Confidential correspondence of Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi to Japanese Foreign Minister Aoki relating to Korean political refugees abroad; the Seoul-W0nsan R.R. and Seoul-Shin'iju R.R.; the foreign settlement at Masan; and the misconduct of Russian sailors in Pusan. Record of the audience given by the Korean Emperor and the Korean Crown Prince to Hayashi and Nishiwaki Chotaro, Manager of the Inchon Branch of the First Bank of Tokyo. Documents relating to German railroad interests in Korea; Russian timber concession on Ullungdo Island; and Japanese land acquisition in Seoul. Confidential report from Hayashi to Aoki relating to Russo-Japanese relations in Korea and the political situation in Seoul after the Bombing Incident of May 13, 1899. July 10 - Dec. 23, 1899.
  286, 287 on the same frame. 280-294 in English.
- Confidential correspondence to and from Japanese consular posts in Korea, (Meiji 33-nen kimitsu kakkan ofuku), 1899; 80 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 72.
  Confidential documents relating to the Bombing Incident of May 13, 1899; the misconduct of Russian sailors in Pusan; the Seoul-W0nsan and Seoul-Pusan railroads; and Japanese settlements in Pyongyang. Documents relating to Korean political refugees; the acquisition of land by the Russians in Masan and by the French in Pusan; and the popular uprising in Kobu in the North Ch0lla Province.
  Illegible frames: 9, 10.
- Correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Home Office, (Meiji 32-nen honsho oraishin), 1899; 127 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 73.
  Documents relating to the Seoul-Inchon R.R.; the recall of Pak Y0ng-hyo from exile; the arrival of the new Russian Minister to Korea, Pavlov; and the conflict between the Palace and the Korean government. General administrative reports from the Japanese Legation in Korea. Documents relating to the new Korean budget, economic and political conditions in Korea; and Russian administrative measures in the Liaotung Peninsula. Jan. 6 - Dec. 16, 1899.
  Missing frame: 81. Illegible fr.: 85, 125.
- Confidential correspondence received by the Japanese Legation in Korea from the Home Office, (Meiji 32-nen kimitsu honsho rai), 1899; 125 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 74.
  Confidential correspondence from Japanese Foreign Minister Aoki to Japanese Minister in Korea Kato Masuo relating to the wish of Yi Jun-yong, the grandson of the Taew0ngun, to establish residence in Japan; and to other Korean political refugees in Japan. Documents relating to political changes in Korea after the arrival of Pavlov, the new Russian Minister to Korea; the cancellation of permission to Pak Y0ng-hyo to return to Korea; Japan's agricultural development policy in Korea; Russo-Korean negotiations for a loan; and the Russian acquisition of whaling rights in Korean waters. Texts of the Korean-Japanese Fishery Agreement (Draft). Confidential correspondence from Aoki to Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke relating to the case of Yi Chun-yong; and the opening of Kunsan, Masan, and S0ngjin. Copy of a report from Japanese Minister to China Yano Fumio to Aoki relating to the Anglo-Russian convention on China signed at St. Petersburg in 1899. Documents relating to the transfer of the railroad concession between Seoul and Inchon from an American firm to a Japanese firm; and German-Japanese relations in Korea concerning the construction of the Seoul-W0nsan R.R. Jan. 16 - Nov. 28, 1899.
  Illegible frames: 32, 64, 97, 98. 115 contains map. 15, 68-70, 73, 74 in English.
- Diplomatic correspondence received from the Korean government, (Meiji 32-nen Gaibu raishin), 1899; 87 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 75.
  Documents relating to the transfer of railroad rights from an American firm to a Japanese firm in Korea; the foreign settlements at Chinnamp'o, Mokp'o, Kunsan, Masan, S0ngjin, and Pyongyang. Texts of an agreement between Korea and Russia relating to forestry and lumber in the Yalu and Tumen River valleys, and on Ullungdo Island. Jan. 9 - Dec. 23, 1899.
  Illegible frame: 43. 59-64 in Korean.
- Diplomatic correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Korean government, (Meiji 32 nen gaibu oshin), 1899; 156 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 76.
  Documents relating to the Seoul Inchon R. R. originally planned by an American, Morse; the construction of a wave breaker in Mokp'o harbor by the Japanese; the construction of Seoul-Pusan R. R.; trade at Pyongyang, Masan, and Songjin; the opening of Pyongyang; and Korean currency. Jan. 2 - Dec. 25, 1899.
  Illegible frame: 11 (map). 12, 125 contain maps. 10-13 in Korean.
- Telegrams received from Japanese consular posts in Korea, (Meiji 32-nen kaku ryojikan dempo raishin), 1899; 106 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 77.
  Telegrams from Japanese consuls in Korea to Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi. Oct. 11 - Dec. 28, 1899 and Jan. 9 - Oct. 7, 1900.
- Copies of European-language telegrams sent by the Japanese Legation in Korea to the Home Office and other Japanese diplomatic posts since July 1899 (Meiji 32 nin 7-gatsu iko honsho sonota obun dempo oshin hikae), 63 frames. (Reel 6)
  Box/Folder 2: 78.
  English-language telegrams sent by Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi to Japanese Foreign Minister Aoki. July 17 - Dec. 25, 1899.
  Illegible frame: 20.
- Copies of European-language telegrams received by the Japanese Legation in Korea from the Home Office and other Japanese diplomatic posts since July 1899 (Meiji 32-nen 7-gatsu iko honsho sonota obun dempo raishin hikae), 19 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 79.
  Japanese Foreign Minister Aoki's reply to the Japanese Minister in Seoul concerning the Russian concession on Ullungdo Island and Korean students in Tokyo. July 28 - Dec. 26, 1899.
- Documents relating to the Seoul-Pusan Railroad, (Meiji 33-nen Keifu tetsudo ni kansuru shorui), 1900; 219 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 80.
  Documents relating to the construction and maintenance of the Seoul-Pusan R. R. Apr. 6, 1896 - Dec. 12, 1900.
  Illegible frames: 131-134, 181-183, 192. Two different frames numbered 197.
- Confidential correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea to the Home Office, (Meiji 33-nen kimitsu honsho oshin), 1900; 310 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 81.
  Correspondence from Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi to the Home Office relating to his audience with the Korean Emperor; the opening of Pyongyang; and the intervention of the American Minister in Korean politics. A summary of a Russian newspaper article on Korea dated Nov. 5, 1899. Documents relating to the timber concession on Ullungdo Island; the Pusan Incident involving Russian sailors; the case of Maeil Shinmun (Daily News) in Seoul; the lease of land in Masan and on K0jedo and Kohado Islands; the activities of Hwalbindang (Pauper's Party) in South Ch'ungch'0ng Province; foreign loans to Korea; the case of An Ky0ng-su; the attitude of the Korean Emperor towards the Boxer Rebellion; the transfer of Korean Minister to Japan Yi Ha-y0ng, and the appointment of Cho Py0ng-sik as his successor; the secret Korean-Japanese treaty of 1900; the audience granted to the Russian Minister, and the Russian request for the extension of timber rights along the Yalu River. Jan. 11 - Nov. 27, 1900.
  Missing frame: 155. 239, 240 on one frame. 153, 154 contain maps. 21-26a, 241-244 in English.
- Correspondence received by the Japanese Legation in Korea from Japanese consular posts in Korea, -- Part I (Meiji 33-nen kakkan raishin--I), 1900; 56 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 82.
  Report from Japanese Consul at Inchon Ijuin to Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi concerning the activities of the Hwalbindang group. Reports from various Japanese consuls concerning the reaction of Koreans to the Boxer Rebellion. May 15 - Nov. 25, 1900.
  Illegible frame: 21. 56 contains the left side of frame 1 in Folder 83.
- Correspondence received by the Japanese Legation in Korea from Japanese consular posts in Korea, --Part II (Meiji 33-nen kakkan raishin--II), 1900; 42 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 83.
  Reports dated Aug. 9 - Oct. 30, 1900 received from the Kunsan Branch of the Japanese Consulate at Mokp'o regarding the monopoly of Korean merchants in that area. Reports received from Japanese police chiefs in Kunsan and Masan regarding the activities of the Hwalbindang group.
  The left side of frame 1 is on frame 56b in Folder 82. 9b-11 in Korean.
- Confidential correspondence received by the Japanese Legation in Korea from Japanese consular posts in Korea, (Meiji 33-nen kaku ryojikan kimitsu raishin), 1900; 110 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 86.
  Documents relating to the An Ky0ng-su Incident; the arrival of a Russian warship at Mokp'o; the reaction of the Koreans to the Boxer Rebellion; the circulation of anti-government leaflets; popular uprisings in the S0ngjin and Kilchu areas; and the Russian interests in the Kunsan area. Feb. 8 - May 24, 1900.
  109, 110 contain plans.
- Confidential correspondence received by the Japanese Legation in Korea from Japanese consular posts in Korea, (Meiji 33-nen kaku ryojikan kimitsu raishin), 1900; 134 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 87.
  Documents relating to the misconduct of Russian sailors in Pusan; the Ullungdo Island and Kohado Island questions; telegraph line between Pusan and Masan; the movement of Russian warships near Pusan; the activities of a Russian, Myzenko [?], in Masan, Kunsan, and Pusan areas. Documents concerning Hwalbindang. Report concerning the activities of Han Kyu-s0k. Feb. 22 - Oct. 31, 1900.
  65 contains map. 107-119a in Korean.
- Confidential correspondence received by the Japanese Legation in Korea from the Home Office, (Meiji 33-nen kimitsu honsho raishin), 1900; 65 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 88.
  Confidential correspondence from Japanese Foreign Minister Aoki to Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi relating to the movement of Japanese warships in the southern Korean waters; articles published in the Mainichi Shimbun concerning Russo-Japanese relations in regard to Kohado Island and the Pusan Incident. Documents relating to foreign loans to Korea, and mining concessions by the Korean government to foreigners. Summary of conversations between Korean Minister to Japan Hy0n Y0ng-un and chief of the Bureau of Foreign Trade Sugimura Fukashi. Summary of conversations between the Russian Minister to Japan and Aoki. Jan. 19 - Dec. 27, 1900.
  Illegible frames: 16, 17. 4 contains Japanese newspaper clippings; 13, 14 contain Japanese and English newspaper clippings.
- Diplomatic correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea to the Korean government, (Meiji 33-nen Gaibu oshin), 1900; 41 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 89.
  Diplomatic notes sent to Korean Foreign Minister Pak Che-sun from Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi concerning Japanese merchants and fishermen in Korean treaty ports. Jan. 8 - Dec. 20, 1900.
- Diplomatic correspondence received by the Japanese Legation in Korea from the Korean government, (Meiji 33-nen Gaibu raishin), 1900; 47 frames. (Reel 18)
  Box/Folder 2: 90.
  Diplomatic correspondence between Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke and Korean Foreign Minister Pak Che-sun relating to Japanese navigation in Korean waters; Japanese instructors in Korea; and the arrival of the mission of Shibusawa Eiichi to Korea. Jan. 25 - Dec. 12, 1900.
- Correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea to the Japanese consular posts in Korea, (Meiji 32-nen kaku ryojikan oshin), 1899; 13 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 92.
  Instructions of Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke to the Japanese consuls in Pusan, W0nsan, Masan, and S0ngjin relating to Japanese whaling in Korean waters and other miscellaneous matters. Feb. 15 - Sept. 12, 1899.
- Telegrams of the Japanese Legation in Korea to the Home Office, (Meiji 32-nen, 33-nen honsho dempo oshin), 1899, 1900; 76 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 93.
  Telegrams of Japanese ministers in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke and Kafo Masuo, and Chargé d'Affaires Hioki to Japanese Foreign Minister Aoki relating to Kohado Island, Seoul-Inchon R. R., Japanese whaling in Korean waters, Seoul-W0nsan R. R., the popular uprising in Kobu; and the trade and commerce in Korea. Jan. 9, 1899 - Sept. 12, 1900.
- Copies of confidential European-language telegrams received by the Japanese Minister in Korea from the Home Office and other Japanese diplomatic posts, (Meiji 33-nen kimitsu honsho sonota obun dempo hikae), 1900; 90 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 96.
  Copies of English-language telegrams from the Japanese Minister in Korea to Japanese Foreign Minister Aoki relating to Pak Y0ng-hyo; An Ky0ng-su; Russian interests in Korea; the Boxer Rebellion; and the withdrawal of Japanese government's support of the loan agreement between the First Bank of Tokyo and the Korean government negotiated through J. M. Brown, the British financial adviser to the Korean government. Jan. 25 - Oct. 6, 1900.
  Missing frame: 39. 26, 27 on one frame; 76, 77 on one frame; 88, 89 on one frame.
- Copies of confidential European-language telegrams received by the Japanese Legation in Korea from the Home Office and other Japanese diplomatic posts, --Part II (Meiji 33-nen kimitsu honsho sonota obun raishin hikai--II), 1900; 57 frames. (Reel 6)
  Box/Folder 2: 97.
  English-language telegrams from Japanese diplomats in China, France, the United States and other countries relating to international politics involving China and Korea, addressed to the Home Office and transmitted to the Japanese Minister in Seoul. Oct. 8 - Dec. 31, 1900.
- Telegrams to and from the Japanese Legation in Korea and Japanese consular posts in Korea, (Meiji 33-nen kaku ryojikan dempo orai), 1900; 45 frames. (Reel 18)
  Box/Folder 2: 98.
  Telegraphic correspondence to and from Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke and the Japanese consuls in Korea. Mar. 29, - Nov. 19, 1900.
- Confidential correspondence to and from Japanese consular posts in Korea, (Meiji 34-nen ryojikan kimitsu ofuku), 1901; 39 frames. (Reel 6)
  Box/Folder 2: 99.
  Confidential correspondence to and from Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi with Japanese Foreign Minister Komura and the manager of the [UNK] Branch of the First Bank of Tokyo concerning prohibition of the circulation of Japanese bank notes in Korea. June 11 - Dec. 6, 1901. Confidential reports from Kawakami Tateichiro, head of the Japanese Legation's office at S0ngjin, to Hayashi concerning the disturbances among the Koreans in the S0ngjin area. Mar. 10 - Nov. 17, 1901.
  Illegible frames: 10, 11a.
- Correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea to and from the Home Office, (Meiji 34-nen honsho orai shin), 1901; 89 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 102.
  Correspondence between Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi and Japanese Foreign Minister Kato Takaaki relating to the Korean-Belgian commercial treaty. Documents relating to the Russian occupation of Kando; popular disturbances in the S0ngjin area and on Chejudo Island; mining interests of the United States and France in Korea; and the Korean-French special postal agreement. Translation of an extract of a report written by the American Minister in Korea concerning American commercial interests in Korea. Jan. 18 - Dec. 18, 1901.
  Missing frame: 6. Illegible fr.: 20a, 27, 28a.
- Confidential correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea to the Home Office, (Meiji 34-nen honsho kimitsu oshin), 1901; 276 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 104.
  Documents relating to the request of the Korean Foreign Office to the Japanese government for the extension of the period of employment of former Japanese Minister to Korea Kato Masuo as an adviser to the Korean government; Japanese ginseng merchants in Korea; the revision of mining concessions to the United States and Great Britain; American water works project in Seoul; the Korean Emperor's audience given to Russian Minister to Korea Pavlov and to a Russian envoy, Evgenii Smirnov, and their activities in Korea; the imprisonment of Kim Yong-jun in connection with the struggle between the pro-Russian and pro-American political groups involving Kang S0k-ho, Min Y0ng-hwan, Min Ky0ng-sik, Yi Yong-ik, Pak Che-sun and others; the British financial adviser to the Korean government, J. M. Brown; Korean-French international postal agreement; the difficulties among Korea, Japan, and France in regard to coal mines and railroads in the Pyongyang area; and the Sino-Korean boundary dispute and Russian mediation. Summary of the audience given by the Korean Emperor to Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke with regard to the political developments in Seoul. Jan. 5 - Dec. 29, 1901.
  Illegible frame: 107. 13b contains map. 14-17 in Korean; 160, 161, 165, 166a in English.
- Copies of documents relating to a loan for the purchase of land for the Seoul-Inchon Railroad (Keijin tetsudo fusetsuchi daikin tatekae hikae), 40 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 105.
  Documents relating to the transfer of the concession for the construction of the Seoul-Inchon Railroad from an American, James R. Morse, to a group of Japanese in Nov. 1897. "Schedule Annex A. Certified copy of a concession for a railroad to connect Seoul and Chemulpo in favor of James R. Morse." Documents relating to a loan from the Bank of Japan to the Korean government, March 30, 1895.
  21 is followed by 19 unnumbered frames in English. 8a in English; 17b-19a in Korean.
- Copies of miscellaneous documents in European languages, (Meiji 31 nen obun monjo sattetsu), 1898; 5 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 106.
  Contract for the employment of a German, Eugene Lessing, as a Palace Guard, signed Sept. 3, 1898 in Shanghai.
- Diplomatic correspondence received by the Japanese Legation in Korea from the Korean government, (Meiji 34-nen gaibu raishin), 1901; 9 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 107.
  Diplomatic notes received from the Korean Foreign Office concerning the illegal arrest of Koreans by the Japanese police. May 17 - Dec. 24, 1901.
- Copies of Japanese-language telegrams, (Meiji 34-nen wabun dempo hikae), 1901; 50 frames.
  Box/Folder 2: 108.